

IVAN IVKOVIĆ

Backend Software Developer / Technical Support Specialist / Product Manager ♥ ZAGREB, CROATIA +385992763150

o DETAILS o

Zagreb, Croatia +385992763150 ivan.ivkovichh@gmail.com

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

1991-11-07 Zadar, Croatia

NATIONALITY

Croatian

○ SOCIAL PROFILES ○

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivan -ivkovi%C4%87-1b601953/

o SKILLS o

GoLang

PHP - Codeigniter, Custom MVC

Javascript - jQuery, Typescript, Node.js

Linux

Git

Kubernetes

A2P - P2A Messaging

C++

Python

○ LANGUAGES ○

English

PROFILE

Backend microservices and web developer, experienced in customer support and product management in the messaging industry with overall 6 years of work experience in the IT in general, and open to adapt to additional technologies and responsibilities.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Backend Software Developer at IDB Mobile, Zagreb

April 2018 - July 2018

Software development in the backend administration application, and microservice-oriented CMS in the Google Cloud, such as:

- Independent microservice development in GoLang (or rewriting from Typescript), such as SMTP mailing application
- Content management system development in GoLang (independent microservices in GRPC as backend for a CMS)
- System administration panel plugin development in PHP (billing statistics, inbound and mobile payment traffic details, some frontend work if needed)

Senior Core Product Engineer at Infobip, Zagreb

January 2015 - April 2018

- Providing accurate information and solutions to our premium clients. Maintaining a high level of professionalism and quality in order to successfully satisfy each of their needs in varying critical and non-critical situations.
- · Providing feedback to our partners and internal teams of engineers. This includes gathering specification, service verification and field testing in order to improve our products based on the evolving needs of our customers.
- Managing API product roadmap and documentation, performing continuous quality assurance of present and upcoming product features.
- 2nd line support for SMPP connectivity, HTTP API and software integration related cases, ensuring all work is being done in time and with good practices in place.
- · Messaging system routing monitoring and maintenance; reporting partner related incidents and adjusting suboptimal routes for highest delivery performance.

Web Developer at StartupNomads, VeraciousFood, Zadar (Freelancing)

October 2018 - October 2018

Freelance website and admin CMS development using PHP and Javascript in the following

http://www.startupnomads.com http://www.veraciousfood.com

Client: Federico Baldelli / https://www.linkedin.com/in/federicobaldelli/

∘ HOBBIES ∘

In my personal time, I enjoy playing the guitar, bass, drums and singing and have been performing in numerous local bands and choirs non-professionally. I'm also a big fan of headphones and speakers and maintain a brief collection of high end audio equipment.

Web Developer at Pixplorer, Sportville, Zadar (local startups)

June 2011 - January 2013

- Design and development of a photo sharing Pinterest-like social network and its admin board.
- Design and development of a social network for sport and development of a data entry system.

Website Project Manager at Ziptask, Remote (Freelancing)

April 2014 - June 2014

Ziptask was an online outsourcing services platform that employs project managers to execute the projects of consumers and SMEs.

Freelancing as their project manager, I was managing website projects for Ziptask customers.

INTERNSHIPS

Junior Web Developer at Futuro Internet Studio, Zadar, Croatia

October 2012 - July 2013

Website development and maintenance, website data entry, CMS module construction and maintenance, and project management (JIRA-like) software creation.

EXAMPLE PROJECTS

Projects - Gitlab Repository

https://gitlab.com/ivanivkovic/code-box-public

EDUCATION

Multimedia & Graphics Vocational School, Zadar, Croatia

September 2006 - October 2010

Vocational multimedia & graphics high school in Zadar - a high school program focusing on print, design, multimedia, and computer science, working with:

- Object Oriented Programming (C#, Java)
- Web Programming (PHP, Javascript, XHTML, CSS) and databases (Microsoft Access, MSSQL, and MySQL)
- Multimedia & Graphic Design (Adobe Photoshop, Premiere, Flash, CorelDraw)
- Computer Science and Internet Technologies (general computing & networking)

COURSES

PHP Web Development, Algebra Academy, Zadar Croatia

March 2011 - July 2011

WORK PREFERENCES

Preferences

Acceptable work environments:

- Full-time
- Part-time (temporarily)
- Relocation
- Remote work